{"tossups": [{"question": "Rida Hamida and Ben Vazquez began a regular event to set up these establishments \u201cat every mosque\u201d in Orange County, California, providing their first iftar in June 2017. Marco Gutierrez warned about the proliferation of these establishments, noting \u201cMy culture is a very dominant culture,\u201d in a widely mocked 2016 interview; many critics of that interview also cited an earlier tweet claiming \u201cI love Hispanics!\u201d For ten points, name these establishments that Gutierrez, the leader of Latinos for Trump, warned would be \u201con every corner\u201d if Mexican immigration continued.", "answer": "<b> taco truck</b>s (prompt on partial answers, like \u201cfood trucks\u201d or answers related to selling tacos)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In the essay<em> Blind Nightmare</em>, this author examined the impact of a 1995 terrorist attack on his home country, and this author interviewed people about those attacks in his work<em> Underground</em>. In addition to the essay collection<em> What I Talk About When I Talk About Running</em>, this author wrote a novel set in a timeline with two moons, which follows Tengo and Aomame. For ten points, name this author who was inspired by Aum Shinrikyo\u2019s gas attacks to write<em> 1Q84</em>, who also wrote<em> Killing Commendatore</em> and <em>Norwegian Wood</em>.", "answer": "Haruki<b> Murakami</b>", "metadata": "Literature - World Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "As White House Communications Director, this man remarked that the greatest vacuum in American politics was to the right of Ronald Reagan. This man criticized the \u201cgiant masquerade ball\u201d of the 1992 Democratic National Convention in a speech that described a \u201creligious war\u201d for the \u201csoul of America\u201d. This coiner of the term \u201cSilent Majority\u201d delivered the \u201cculture war\u201d speech in a failed attempt to gain the 1992 Republican nomination. For ten points, name this paleoconservative former Nixon adviser, the Reform Party nominee in 2000.", "answer": "Patrick<b> Buchanan</b> Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This monument was bankrolled after the film<em> The Deer Hunter</em> inspired Jan Scruggs to form a fund. Visitors often use crayons to trace this monument\u2019s etchings onto a piece of paper, a ritual known as\u201crubbing.\u201d The Mayaguez Affair marks the final date new entries were accepted into this monument. Ross Perot derided this monument\u2019s architect as an eggroll over its design, which was insulted as a \u201cblack gash of shame.\u201d Names of servicemen are listed on a granite wall on this monument. For ten points, identify this Maya Lin monument that commemorates a war in Southeast Asia.", "answer": "<b> Vietnam War</b> memorial", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "W. A. Boyle, a head of this union, ordered the death of reformer Joseph Yablonski. Illinois Governor John Riley Tanner promised he would shoot up rail cars with strikebreakers against this union in the Battle of Virden. Strikes called by this union led to racial unrest at Pana, Illinois. This organization sought benefits for people suffering from Black Lung Disease. A co-founder of the CIO, John Lewis, was also a president of this union. In 1894, this union called for the bituminous coal miners\u2019 strike. For ten points, name this union which represents coal miners.", "answer": "<b> UMW</b>A (<b>United Mine Workers</b> of America)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This action unintentionally created an exclave that became the short-lived Free State of Bottleneck. The Hauptwache Incident during this action prompted racist campaigns against the \u201cBlack Shame,\u201dcolonial troops participating in this action. This action was prematurely ended by the Young Plan and was intended to guarantee continued reparations payments by its target country. French and Belgian troops invaded the Ruhr in, for ten points, what military action where Allied troops were stationed in post-WWI western Germany?", "answer": "<b> Occupation of the Rhineland</b> (prompt on \u201cOccupation of the Ruhrland\u201d until mention)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s daughter Winnaretta became the Princess of Polignac. This inventor\u2019s first patent, a machine to drill rock, was sold to the I and M Canal Building Company. Orlando Potter helped this man create a patent pool, for which this man would earn royalties on products such as the \u201cturtle back\u201d. Edward Cabot Clark helped this man develop installment plans. This man\u2019s products use a \u201cvibrating shuttle\u201d and used the eye pointed needle and lock stitch. For ten points, name this man who founded a namesake sewing machine company.", "answer": "Isaac<b> Singer</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The authorship of this hymn is commonly credited to Latino Malabranca Orsini or Thomas of Celano. The second line of this hymn says that the titular concept will dissolve the world in ashes. This hymn is quoted after the titular \u201cdrumroll\u201d in a Haydn symphony and features prominently in Berlioz\u2019s<em> Symphonie</em> <em>Fantastique</em>. This hymn forms the \u201csequence\u201d section of a requiem, which in the requiems by Mozart and Verdi, follows the Kyrie. For ten points, name this Latin hymn whose title refers to a \u201cday of wrath\u201d.", "answer": "<b> Dies irae</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This artist connected 760 bicycles together for one work, and photographed himself dropping a 2,000 year old urn on the floor for another. This artist released a heavy metal song detailing his imprisonment for supposed economic crimes, and salvaged wood from temples to make a map of his country. This artist and created over 100 million porcelain sunflower seeds for the Tate Modern. For ten points, name this Chinese artist and activist who consulted on Beijing\u2019s Bird\u2019s Nest Stadium.", "answer": "<b> Ai</b> Weiwei", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {}, {"question": "Description acceptable. Vincenz Fettmilch caused one of these actions in Frankfurt that was reversed by imperial intervention. All Saint\u2019s Day was set as a deadline for one of these events, which began a massacre in York. The Whitehall Conference reversed that one of these actions because it found that no parliamentary law specifically banned one group from England. That group was subject to a 1290 edict by Edward I responding in fear of ritual murders. For ten points, name this anti-semitic action where one religious group were forced to leave their country.", "answer": "<b> Expulsions of Jew</b>ish people (accept<b> pogrom</b> until \u201creversed,\u201d take anything about ejecting Jewish people from their homes)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this wealthy Southeast Asian kingdom that once ruled modern-day Thailand.", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Ayutthaya</b> (prompt on \u201cSiam\u201d or \u201cThailand\u201d)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>An amendment to one of these documents banning all alcoholic beverages was the first in the U.S. James H. Lane drafted one of these documents while leading the \u201cRed</b> <b>Legs\u201d. Stephen Douglas sided with (+)</b> <b>Thomas Ewing Jr. and against James Buchanan</b> <b>in opposing one of these documents that led to the resignation of Robert J. Walker. Solon Thatcher and (*)</b> Clarina Nichols spoke out during deliberations over one of these documents in 1859; that free-state one of these documents opposed the Lecompton one and was named for Wyandotte. For 10 points, name these governing documents for a \u201cBleeding\u201d state passed before the Civil War.", "answer": "<b> constitution</b>s of<b> Kansas</b> (prompt on constitutions)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "These people had to work three days a week in the (*) </b> <em>barshchina</em> or pay the<em> obrok</em> levy. One decree affecting these people kept a temporary obligation phase but gave them personal freedoms and the right to buy land and property. For ten points, name these Russian agricultural workers freed by Tsar Alexander II.", "answer": "Russian<b> serf</b> (accept<b> peasant</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>This team was the last NFL team to start a black quarterback, doing so when backup Geno Smith replaced the regular starter; the following day, GM Jerry Reese and head</b> <b>coach Ben McAdoo were fired. This team named a stadium where (+)</b> <b>Jimmy Hoffa was</b> <b>supposedly buried; the 2010 demolition of that stadium in favor of MetLife Stadium proved the urban legend wrong. The (*)</b> Patriots failed to complete their perfect 2007 season because this team beat them in Super Bowl 42, earning Eli Manning the first of his two titles. For ten points, name this football team that shares its home stadium with the New York Jets.", "answer": "New York<b> Giants</b> (prompt on New York)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A ruler of this state criticized sailors for carrying wine, and was thus chucked overboard. That ruler notably insulted an emir by noting \u201cI only see women here!\u201d, referencing the (+) tagelmust veil worn by the emir. Torrential rain saved this state\u2019s leader Ibn Tumart at the Battle of al-Buhayra. The fortress of (*)</b> Tinmel became a center of this state, whose name meant\u201cthe unifiers\u2019. This state lost the Battle of Las Navas de Tolosa and was later conquered by the Nasrids of Granada. Partially succeeded by the Marinids, for ten points, name this successor to the Almoravid dynasty.", "answer": "<b> Almohad</b> Dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>In this city, the airships Eagle and Arrow were constructed by John Montgomery as he pioneered the concept of heavier-than-air flight. The hard disk drive was invented in this</b> <b>city at IBM\u2019s (+)</b> <b>West Coast headquarters. During a period of expansion under \u201cDutch\u201d</b> <b>Hamann, Alviso and Cambrian Park merged into this city. This city served as (*)</b> California\u2019s first state capital but is now the seat of Santa Clara county. eBay and Adobe are headquartered in this city. Cupertino lies just west of, for ten points, what largest city and economic center of Silicon Valley?", "answer": "<b> San Jose</b> Page 11", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "<b>Hiram T. Smith is considered the only casualty in this conflict, which saw lumberjacks defend the home of Barbary War hero William Eaton at the Battle of Caribou. John (+) Baker was arrested in the lead up to this war, while Isaac Hodgson and Winfield Scott led troops. In order to resolve this war, Jared Sparks helped find a map with a line drawn by (*) </b> Benjamin Franklin, while the other side hid the Mitchell Map. This war, also known as the Pork and Beans War, saw the French speaking Brayons declare the Republic of Madawaska. Ended by the Webster-Ashburton Treaty, for ten points, name this 1838-39 conflict over the New Brunswick-Maine border.", "answer": "<b> Aroostook</b> War ", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Major Lorenzo Carter was said to be the entire law of this city, once threatening</b> <b>the father of John Omic after Omic chased a girl with a knife. A 1986 stunt in this city</b> <b>saw the release of almost one and half-million (+)</b> <b>balloons, which led to the death</b> <b>of two boaters. Irish immigrants in this city were said to live in shanties at Irishtown</b> <b>Bend in this city\u2019s (*) </b> Flats district. Standard Oil began as a partnership in this city. Case Western, named for being in the formerly Connecticut Western Reserve, is located in this city. The Cuyahoga River caught fire in, for ten points, what second largest Ohio city located on Lake Erie.", "answer": "<b> Cleveland</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "As a result of this man\u2019s demise, his son had to be placed on the throne by the Russians in the War of Polish Succession.", "answer": "<b> Augustus II</b> (accept<b> Augustus the Strong</b>; accept<b> Frederick Augustus I</b>) Page 12", "metadata": "History - European History"}], "bonuses": []}